Pratheep Kumar Chelladurai

PERSONALITY: ISFP-T

www.pratheepkumar.design • pratheepkumar1@gmail.com • +91 - 9791270872 • linkedin.in/pratheepkumarc

CAREER SUMMARY

My passion for design is fuelled by the vastness of the design spectrum. From consumer insights to product vision to optimized user experiences - in my career, I faced a wide range of challenges that strengthened my design and problem-solving skills. My vision is to gain experiences from every aspect of design and channelise it to become a multifaceted creative who specialises in providing an intuitive, immersive and inclusive technology experience irrespective of the medium.

Current Interests: Data Visualisation, Inclusive Design Approach and Designing for Connected Devices.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer

Qube Cinema Technologies, Chennai

Jun 2017 - Present (2.5 Years*)

UX/UI Design Internship

Qube Cinema Technologies, Chennai

Jan 2017 - Mar 2017 (3 Months)

Revamped existing products to improve user engagement; Designed UI components with accessbility complainces; Designed the user experience for an analytics component for generating insights to be used by movie distributors and theatre owners

Ideated and designed single sign-on flow for Qube's B2C products;

Made multiple customisable animated greetings templates (rendered in HTML5) to be run on cinema screens; Made interaction animations, icons and illustrations

EDUCATION

B.Tech Information Technology

SSN College of Engineering, Chennai

Jun 2013 - Apr 2017 (4 Years)

Final Year Project: Speech interface for developing HTML based website. Designed the official website for SSN Instincts (Cultural Program) which was used by 1000s of students in and around Tamil Nadu province.

COURSES

Summer School

Copenhagen Institute of Interaction Design

Dec 2018 (3 Weeks)

UX Design Certification

UX Mint Design Academy, Chennai

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018 (6 Months)

Topics: Intro to Service Design; Inclusive Design; Behaviors & it's Impacts. Mini Projects: Designed conceptual service design for Post Flood Rehabilitation; Changing behaviors of people to prevent littering in Ferry Boat Terminal by applying behavioral biases.; Designed Conceptual Model to make the life of children at child care institutions more inclusive.

Topics: UX Researh Methodologies; Conception Process; Prototyping; Projects: Designed and Prototyped Single Player Marketplace Mobile App for Buying and Selling used E-Products.



Pratheep Kumar Chelladurai

PERSONALITY: ISFP-T

www.pratheepkumar.design • pratheepkumar1@gmail.com • +91 - 9791270872 • linkedin.in/pratheepkumarc

COMMUNITIES

Club Lead and Volunteer

SSN Design Club

2016 - 2017 (1 Year)

Volunteer

Sri Jayendra Interact Club

2011 - 2012 (1 Year)

AWARDS

Spot Award for Design Excellence

Qube Cinema Town Hall

Aug 2018

Best Implementation Award

32 Hours Startup Challenge

Aug 2016

Co-led the official design club of my college which consisted of about 30 designers and art enthusiasts. Conducted skil sharing sessions and supported the college community by regularly designing printables and official websites for the significant events that happened in our college.

I was part of a 20 members team and my responsibility included collecting usable things (clothes, books and other accessories) from students of our school and handed over to orphanage homes. Visited the orphanage home which includes children below 18 year and there we conducted activities, prepared foods and created awareness about education.

Appreciation for designing a intuitive data visualization feature in a week. And contribution in providing simpler and easier mechanism for the day to day operations people in their approval process of complex data sets.

Recognition to our 3 members team for implementing decision making tools for credit aiding in banking service. I contributed as User Experience and User Interface Designer during this challenge.

SKILLS

Research • Design • Development

Tools

OTHER INTERESTS

Professional Cricket • Travelling • Photography • Sketching

Contextual Research, Empathy Mapping, Information Architecture,
Card Sorting, Rapid Prototyping, Heuristic Evaluation, Wireframing,
Data Visualization, Design Documentation, Interactive Prototyping,
HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Python (Basics)

Miro, Whimsical, Sketch, Figma, Adobe Creative Suite, Principle, Invision, Webflow, Abstract, Airtable